[
{
    "question": "What is the range of heading tags in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<h1> to <h5>",
      "<h1> to <h4>",
      "<h1> to <h6>",
      "<h1> to <h3>"
    ],
    "answer": "<h1> to <h6>"
  },
  {
    "question": "In HTML, data inside a <p> tag are:",
    "options": [
      "Preserved exactly as typed",
      "Ignored and collapsed into a single space",
      "Converted into tabs",
      "Converted into underscores"
    ],
    "answer": "Ignored and collapsed into a single space"
  },
  {
    "question": "In HTML, text inside the <pre> tag:",
    "options": [
      "Collapses multiple spaces into one",
      "Preserves all spaces and line breaks exactly as typed",
      "Converts all text to uppercase",
      "Ignores spaces and line breaks"
    ],
    "answer": "Preserves all spaces and line breaks exactly as typed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is Unpaired tags?",
    "options": [
      "<b>",
      "<br>",
      "<p>",
      "<h1>"
    ],
    "answer": "<br>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is Paired tags?",
    "options": [
      "<img>",
      "<br>",
      "<hr>",
      "<h1>"
    ],
    "answer": "<h1>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the fallowing is correct for inline html element?",
    "options": [
      "<b>",
      "<h1>",
      "<p>",
      "<pre>"
    ],
    "answer": "<b>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are block-level HTML elements?",
    "options": [
      "<b>",
      "<mark>",
      "<h6>",
      "<i>"
    ],
    "answer": "<h6>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about <span>?",
    "options": [
      "It displays text exactly as typed.",
      "represent portion of text inside a paragraph.",
      "It automatically creates a new paragraph",
      "It is a block-level element that starts on a new line"
    ],
    "answer": "represent portion of text inside a paragraph."
  },
  {
    "question": "Every HTML element contains which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Opening  & Closing Tag",
      "Content of the Tag",
      "Attribute of the tag.",
      "The value assigned to the attribute",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about HTML attributes?",
    "options": [
      "Attributes are written inside the closing tag",
      "Attributes are always written in upper case only",
      "Attributes provide additional information about an element",
      "Attributes are mandatory to html elements."
    ],
    "answer": "Attributes provide additional information about an element"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag is used to display strikethrough text?",
    "options": [
      "<del>",
      "<s>",
      "<strike>",
      "<u>"
    ],
    "answer": "<del>"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the formula of water be written in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "H<sub>2</sub>O",
      "H<sup>2</sup>O",
      "H2O",
      "H<mark>2</mark>O"
    ],
    "answer": "H<sub>2</sub>O"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can “square of 5” be written in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "5<sup>2</sup>",
      "5<sub>2</sub>",
      "<b>5^2</b>",
      "5<mark>2</mark>"
    ],
    "answer": "5<sup>2</sup>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag is used to display the largest heading in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<h1>",
      "<h6>",
      "<h3>",
      "<b>"
    ],
    "answer": "<h1>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct HTML syntax to define an abbreviation “W3C” with full form “World Wide Web Consortium”?",
    "options": [
      "<abbr title=\"World Wide Web Consortium\">W3C</abbr>",
      "<abbr>W3C</abbr>",
      "<acronym title=\"World Wide Web Consortium\">W3C</acronym>",
      "<abbr title=\"W3C\">World Wide Web Consortium</abbr>",
      "<acronym title=\"W3C\">World Wide Web Consortium</acronym>"
    ],
    "answer": "<abbr title=\"World Wide Web Consortium\">W3C</abbr>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to create scrolling text “Hello World” in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<marquee>Hello World</marquee>",
      "<scroll>Hello World</scroll>",
      "<scrolltext>Hello World</scrolltext>",
      "<move>Hello World</move>"
    ],
    "answer": "<marquee>Hello World</marquee>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to print the data reverse form?",
    "options": [
      "<bdo dir=\"rtl\">Hello World</bdo>",
      "<bdo direction=\"rtl\">Hello World</bdo>",
      "<bdo dir=\"ltr\">Hello World</bdo>",
      "<bdo textdir=\"rtl\">Hello World</bdo>"
    ],
    "answer": "<bdo dir=\"rtl\">Hello World</bdo>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag is used to make text italic?",
    "options": [
      "<i>",
      "<b>",
      "<u>",
      "<mar"
    ],
    "answer": "<i>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag is used to highlight text using like a marker?",
    "options": [
      "<mark>",
      "<b>",
      "<i>",
      "<u>"
    ],
    "answer": "<mark>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly represents text as bold with semantic meaning in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<p>Please read the <b>terms and conditions</b> carefully.</p>",
      "<p>Please read the <strong>terms and conditions</strong> carefully.</p>",
      "<p>Please read the <u>terms and conditions</u> carefully.</p>",
      "<p>Please read the <mark>terms and conditions</mark> carefully.</p>"
    ],
    "answer": "<p>Please read the <strong>terms and conditions</strong> carefully.</p>"
  }
]
